VEEN FOONG

<u>veenyean@gmail.com</u>

Strategic business planning and development

Brand and product development

Team and project management

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have 20 years of professional experience in strategic business development and consulting, as well as promotions and marketing. Specialize in retail consulting, new business development and analysis, project evaluation and budgeting, project and team development and management, and consumer behavior research. I have extensive experience in helping clients developing business strategies and translating the strategies to brand portfolio objectives, and preparing plans and programs to facilitate the growth of business unit and achieving target goals.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- I have been successful in determining and driving a route-to-market model through identifying and influencing key channels (fast moving consumer goods) and partner relationship, increasing the products sales turnover by 21%, increasing the product distribution by 14% nationwide, and reducing the market hygiene by 5% with SKU rationalization.
- I was responsible for BPR (business process reengineering) for a division with 50 team members in the book retail industry and successfully re-organized the team and reduced staff turnover from 8.8% to 3.5%. With a stabilized and motivated team, I increased the membership revenue by 36% and increased the membership renewal rate by 5.4%.
- I was responsible for strengthening an oil and gas business partnership in the pipeline to expand (in terms of field coverage, to be expanded from one region to 6 regions in Malaysia) and to extend from the current business contract (by increasing 30% of the total contract sales revenue). I was managing the project from business and contract negotiation, strategically ramping up the exclusive team and driving convenience retail advisory to client. The exclusive team is equipped with skills and knowledge to guide petrol convenience stores in order to improve the sales volume and value and profits of respective stores. The exclusive team works closely with the petrol convenience dealers to implement and to execute the merchandising guidelines and disciplines, categories' planograms, correct category flow and proper mapping of the stores in order to increase shopper's frequency, basket size and repeat sales.
- I have increased new businesses (five new agencies in Health and Beauty products, Engine Oil Enhancer products, Medicated Ointment products, Cough Relieve products and Hair Colorant products) with a Distributor. I have successfully developed two new clients in market research and successfully developed a new department (Category Management) in the company by implanting two Space Managers at a new client's premise to guide client on retail space management, category development and assortment optimization.

VEEN FOONG veenyean @gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2012 ~ November 2013 Divisional Manager

DKSH Smollan Field Marketing (M) Sdn Bhd

DKSH Smollan is a joint venture company between DKSH from Switzerland and Smollan from South Africa; it provides point of purchase and brand activation services to grow clients' brands. I reported to the General Manager and was responsible for the following divisions: retail advisory and category management (oil and gas), visual merchandising services, brand activators and retail sales training (consumer electronics), market intelligence division with store audit, mystery shopping, research and image survey (health and beauty, banking, oil and gas, fast moving consumer goods, and departmental store), and business development division to increase the company's revenues.

May 2010 ~ April 2011 Senior Marketing Manager

Popular Book Company (M) Sdn Bhd

Popular Book Company is the largest book retail with 86 locations in Malaysia. I reported to the Executive Director and was responsible for the following divisions: Public Relations and Events, Advertising and Promotions, Club Magazine, Corporate Sales, Graphic Design, CRM Program

December 2006 ~ April 2010 National_Business Manager

DKSH Malaysia Sdn Bhd

DKSH Malaysia is the largest distributor in providing market expansion services for clients. It provides sales and marketing services, logistics, warehousing and retail management services. I reported to the General Manager with 61 direct and indirect subordinates, responsible for the sales, marketing and P&L of a division. Key brand portfolios: Fumakilla, Shaldan, Scholl, Secret Garden, Tiger Balm & Kwan Loong, Aladdin, PZ Cussons, Hoyu, A. Clouet, and Shoon Kee. The total business volume was about USD61 million a year.

August 2005 ~ November 2006 Marketing Division Manager Carrefour Malaysia

Carrefour Malaysia is a Retail Hypermarket format with 28 locations in Malaysia. I reported to the Merchandize Director and was responsible for the following divisions: Advertising and Promotions, Pricing, Loyalty Programs, Corporate Sales, Research and Customer Service.

VEEN FOONG veenyean@gmail.com

January 2001 ~ Jun 2005 Senior Business Manager

DKSH Marketing Services Sdn Bhd

DKSH Marketing Services was formerly known as EAC Holding Malaysia, specialized in market expansion of Fast Moving Consumer Goods, Health Care Products and mobile technology products. I reported to the Group Business Manager and was responsible for the marketing and product management of the following brand portfolio: 3 Legs (Wen Ken), Ansell, Ovaltine, Equal, Gerber, Twinings, and 3M.

May 1994 ~ December 2000 Marketing / Promotions Executive / Senior Graphic

Designer

Body Fashion (M) Sdn Bhd

Body Fashion is the manufacturer of Triumph, a market leader in ladies undergarment. I started as Senior Graphic Designer and was later promoted to Marketing / Promotions Executive. I was given dual role to manage the advertising and promotion department in the Graphic Section and the Bee Dees Club. My responsibility was to build brand loyalty, promote customer retention, and increase sales.

July 1993 ~ April 1994 Graphic Designer

Wang Artor Creative Communication Sdn Bhd

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

- Master of Business Administration (Minor in Marketing), University of Leicester, UK 2009
- Bachelor of Fine Arts in Design Communication, Texas Tech University, Texas, USA 1993

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Retail Marketing by Market 21
- Product Management Training by INSEAD
- Accounts Receivables Best Practices Training by CMCresco Ptd Ltd